backflip.com 2008-06-19

# Backflip | Privacy Policy

Wouldn't it be great if every company respected your privacy on the Internet? You can feel comfortable that Backflip does. In this policy, we describe specifically how Backflip protects your privacy and why you can trust us with your personal information. We aim to provide a secure Web site for you: not only is that respectful, but it's good business. 

You can feel confident that: 

  * We don't view the Bookmarks or Favorites that you add. 
  * We don't view any of the Web pages that you collect. 
  * We don't view your personal information. 
  * We don't permit other Backflip members to view your personal information. 
  * We don't send unwanted email. 

Statement of Policy on Privacy

  1. How We Provide a Secure Environment for Your Data
  2. The Types of Information We Collect From You
  3. How We Use Your Information
  4. How We Disclose Information
  5. How You Can Manage How Much Data to Share or Opt Out of the Services We Provide
  6. How You Can Correct and Update Your Information
  7. How You Can Deactivate Your Backflip Account

[Back to Top]

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact Customer Support by emailing [privacy@backflip.com](mailto:privacy@backflip.com). 

How We Provide A Secure Environment for Your Data

Security measures: Backflip has implemented security measures to protect your information from loss, misuse and alteration. We use industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Third party authorities as well as our internal team periodically review our security system and policy. We constantly upgrade our security systems to ensure that we use the best and most current technology to provide a secure environment for your data. 

Your password: Your information is located in a password-protected area of Backflip. Therefore, you can access your data only with the user name and password that you have chosen. We recommend that you never share your password with anyone. If you share your computer we suggest that you sign out of Backflip before another person uses the computer. 

Backflip employees will never ask you for your password. When you register to become a Backflip user, we ask that you verify your email address. In the event that you forget your password, our system will automatically email you a link directing you to a secure part of our Web site where you create a new password. At no point in this process does any Backflip employee see your password. 

[Back to Top]

The Types of Information We Collect From You

  1. Personally identifiable information 
  2. Information about you without your name 
  3. Aggregated information without your name 

Personally identifiable information: Refers to information that lets us know who you are. In order to register to use Backflip, you will need to give us your name, email address, zip code, year of birth, and country of residence so we can establish your account and make the service valuable for you. 

Information about you without your name: It refers to anonymous information about what you find interesting on the Web, but would never include your name or email address. For example, you might be backflipping a lot of pages about antique radios. Based on this information, we may provide you with information from a partner on where to find antique radios in your area, but we would not sell your name to the partner. 

Aggregated information without your name: Refers to information we gather by aggregating your anonymous information with anonymous information from other users to provide a summary of our users. There is no personally identifiable information in this summary. We may use this information to provide you with insights on how others who are similar to you interact with the Web. For example, we provide a top ten list of the most frequently backflipped links within each of our directories based on our aggregated user information. We may also use this information to inform partners or advertisers about the demographics of our audience. For example, we might inform a partner that 30% of Backflip members are between 25 and 35 years of age. 

Only when you give us your explicit permission will we collect your personally identifiably information. When you join Backflip, we'll ask for your name, email address, zip code, year of birth, country of residence and your preferred user name and password. As you use the service, you will be submitting the names and URLs of Web sites that you have visited. Additionally, you may choose to upload your Bookmarks or Favorites. In all of these cases, we will never associate you per se with any of your data. Nor will Backflip employees view your data, as our security policy calls for dismissal and legal prosecution of any unauthorized person who attempts to access our customers' data. 

[Back to Top]

Like many Web sites, Backflip uses a standard Web technology called "cookies" which helps us to improve your experience. Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your hard drive, not on our site. For example, we use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, and to help you save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site. We do not, and cannot, use cookies to find out the identity of any user. Backflip uses cookies responsibly, creating a great experience for you while respecting your privacy. 

Some of the advertising displayed on our site is delivered by AdForce, LLC. In the course of serving ads, AdForce collects certain non-personally identifiable data by placing a "cookie" (small file containing a unique, randomly selected alphanumeric tag) on a consumer's computer hard drive. The cookies received from banner ads go directly to our ad company, and we do not have access to this information. The non-personally identifiable information collected in connection with a cookie includes: 

  * Browser type (i.e., IE 3.x, etc) 
  * Operating system (i.e., Macintosh, PC, etc) 
  * IP Address of the machine (browser/ proxy) connecting to AdForce (this is not your email address) 
  * Date a particular ad was served 
  * Time a particular ad was served 
  * Advertisement tag (place by a website on a web page to call up an ad). 

This information is used by AdForce to deliver tailored ads to you and in the aggregate for statistical purposes. AdForce uses this information for reporting purposes and to bill our advertisers. Please note that AdForce cannot collect any personal information about you (such as your name, address, phone number or email address) when it delivers ads to our website. If you would like to learn more about AdForce's information gathering practices, or if you would like to "opt-out" of having unique cookie on your hard drive placed by AdForce, please [click here.](http://www.adforce.com/home/privacy/PrivacyPolicy.html)

In addition, when you click on the outside links that you have added, outside links that we present to you or any of our advertisers' ads, you will be transferred to their respective Web sites. Due to the nature of Internet, we do not control the privacy practices of other sites and we are not responsible for such practices as well as their respective content. 

[Back to Top]

How We Use Your Information 

In order to provide a robust experience for our users, we use the information you provide to offer personalized messaging. If you give us permission, we are pleased to email you material about our company or from some of our partners - and we only use your anonymous personal information to do that. 

From time to time, we may send you email about information we think you will find useful, including information about new products and services from our selected partners. We observe the strictest anti-spam standards to ensure that you only receive mailings that are relevant to you. If you prefer not to receive mailings, simply opt out of our mailing list from your profile. You can always change your preference on receiving future mailings at any time (see the How You Can Manage How Much Data to Share or Opt Out of the Services We Provide section below.) 

[Back to Top]

How We Disclose Information

We will never sell, rent, loan or give away your personally identifiable information to third parties without your explicit permission. We may share information about you that is not personally identifiable - it does not contain your name and contact information - with our partners to bring you services that we feel may be beneficial to you. We may at times distribute this anonymous personal information - individually or on an aggregated basis - about our users to advertisers or business partners. As such, your information is still private. We aggregate your information with information supplied by other Backflip users to create a summary of broad demographic profiles of our user base, which contains no personally identifiable information. By sharing this summary information with our partners, we provide advertisements or new features that a broad population will enjoy, yet we do not disclose any personally identifiable data. For example, we provide an aggregated summary such as "30% of users clicked on a specific ad." We never disclose your name or personal profile to our advertisers or partners if you saw or clicked on their advertisements or features unless you have specifically told us this is acceptable. 

As with any other Web site, if law enforcement or judicial authorities require Backflip to provide personally identifiable information about a customer - an extremely unlikely event - we must cooperate if they support their requirement with the necessary legal documentation. 

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that Backflip, Inc., part of, or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information may be one of the transferred assets. 

[Back to Top]

How You Can Manage How Much Data to Share or Opt Out of the Services We Provide

You control the amount of information that you want to share. We only require your name, email address, year of birth, zip code, country of residence, user name and password to enable you to use the service. In order to fully maximize your experience on Backflip, the more information you provide to Backflip, the more useful the service will be. 

Backflip provides you the opportunity to opt out of receiving email and other non-Web site communications from us and from our partners. If you wish to do so, please go to the Backflip site, click on the My Account tab and make your updates there. If you are unable to do so, you may contact Customer Support at [support@backflip.com](mailto:support@backflip.com) or fill out our support form. 

[Back to Top]

How You Can Correct and Update Your Information

You can easily update and/or correct any of the information you have. You can do this by clicking the My Account tab and making your updates there. If you are unable to do so, you may contact Customer Support at [support@backflip.com](mailto:support@backflip.com) or fill out our support form. 

[Back to Top]

How You Can Deactivate your Backflip Account

You can deactivate your Backflip membership at any time. Contact Customer Support at the following email address: [cancel@backflip.com](mailto:cancel@backflip.com). Be sure to include your User name. This completely removes all of your information from our current membership list. 

[Back to Top]

Conclusion 

We at Backflip strongly believe in respecting the privacy of all our users. Users should read this Privacy statement in parallel with our Terms of Use. To ensure that we meet the highest standards in protecting your Privacy, we will update this statement if and when it is necessary. Please check back often to read our most updated statement. If you have any questions regarding this statement, please contact Backflip's Customer Support by using the feedback support form available here, or by sending an email to [privacy@backflip.com](mailto:privacy@backflip.com). 

[Back to Top]
